学习
分享
进步
学习
分享
进步
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
你把我坑苦了
You hung me out to dry.
此话怎讲
How exactly did I do that?
你弄的像是我夺走了
By making it seem like I'm the one
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
你的梦幻婚礼一样
that's taking away your dream wedding.
本来就是你夺走了我的梦幻婚礼
You are the one taking away my dream wedding!
我们要结婚了
We're getting married,
婚礼就小办一场
and it can be as small as possible
只请我们的亲朋好友  好吗
with just our close friends, okay?
我觉得我们应该提拔
I think we should consider promoting Jack Soloff
-杰克·索罗夫做冠名合伙人  -你疯了吗
- to name partner. - Are you crazy?
哈德曼手上有他的把柄
Hardman's got something on him.
如果哈德曼有他的把柄
If Hardman has something on him,
那我们也要抓到他的把柄
then we need to have it on him, too.
你想让我走  召集投票去
You want me gone, call for a vote,
因为我们知道丹尼尔的投资人是怎么回事
'cause we know what's going on with daniel's investor,
而哈维正在去解决问题
and Harvey's about to put a stop to it right now.
我为什么要相信你真的会
Why should I believe you would even live up to
实现你的承诺呢
your end of the bargain?
因为我根本不在乎
Because I don't give a shit
你跟丹尼尔·哈德曼的斗争
about your war with Daniel Hardman.
我想要的只是看着你跪下
All I want to do is see you get down on your knees
然后说  "我退出"
and say, "I quit."
你每天都在违法
You're breaking the law every day.
所以我不该结婚了
Oh, so now I shouldn't get married?
我是说你应该辞职
I'm saying you should quit.
人生走得越远
The longer you go,
钱就越不重要
the less the money matters.
你差点被抓  是吗
You almost got caught, didn't you?
我去找了个人聊了聊
I went to talk to someone.
是谁
Who?
你知道是谁
You know who.
妈妈  爸爸
Mom? Dad!
奶奶  你怎么在这里
Grammy, what are you doing here?
妈妈呢  我想抱抱她
Where's mom? I want to give her a hug.
还有爸爸
Dad, too.
什么
What?
昨晚你让我不要生他们的气  记得吗
You told me not to be mad at them last night, remember?
你说等他们回来我应该跟他们说对不起
You said once they got home I should tell them I was sorry
并给他们个拥抱
and give them a hug.
但他们没叫我起床  所以我没机会
But they didn't wake me up, so I didn't get to,
但我很想抱抱他们
and I want to.
迈克尔  我必须和你说些事情
Michael, I have to tell you something.
什么事
What is it?
你的  你的父母
Your--your parents,
他们昨晚出了一场车祸
last night they were in a car accident.
但他们会好起来的吧
But they're gonna be okay, right?
迈克尔  他们去世了
Michael, they passed away.
什么
What?
不
No.
不  不可能的
No, they can't be.
你说的不对
You're wrong!
我也希望我错了  宝贝
I wish I were, baby.
我希望我
I wish I...
你为什么不叫醒我
Why didn't you wake me up?
我本可以去医院的
I could have gone to the hospital.
我可以见见他们
I could have seen them!
他们没有坚持到医院  亲爱的
They didn't make it to the hospital, sweetheart,
不到迫不得已的时刻我也不想告诉你
and--and I didn't want to tell you until I had to.
你怎么能这么对我
How could you do this to me?
你怎么能不叫醒我
How could you not wake me up?
这么早起来干什么呢
What are you doing up so early?
没什么  就是翻翻这盒旧东西
Oh, nothing, just going through this old box of stuff.
这和你昨晚
Does that have something to do with
跟特雷弗见面有关吗
you seeing Trevor last night?
是啊  有关
Yeah. Yeah, it does.
他的生活还是那么糟吗
Is he still a mess?
不  他其实过得挺好的
No. No, he's actually doing really well.
那是什么意思
So what do you mean?
我的意思是我今天得请个假
I mean, I need to take the day.
你得请假
You need to take the day?
-是的  -出什么事了吗
- Yeah. - Is there something wrong?
不  没什么事
No, nothing's wrong.
就是有些事情需要处理
Just got something I need to do.
好吧
Okay.
皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
杰西卡
Jessica.
杰克
Jack.
你重新考虑我的提议了吗
Did you reconsider my offer?
辞职那件事吗
About resigning?
不  绝不可能
Yeah, no, not a chance.
但公司章程规定需要给你正式通知
But the bylaws require you to be given formal notice so...
你今天召集了
You're calling for
紧急不信任投票
an emergency vote of no confidence today?
是的
Yes.
你数学真差  杰克
Well, you're shitty at math, Jack,
因为就算我们失去了麦肯诺
because even if we lost McKernon,
一个客户也不足以让所有合伙人反对我
one client is not enough to turn the partners against me.
检查一下你的计算器吧  杰西卡
Check your calculator, Jessica,
因为只有一半合伙人支持你
because you only had half the partners,
并且他们中的每个人都要
and every single one of them is about to lose
在一场恶意收购中失去他们最大的客户了
the biggest client to a hostile takeover
而一切都因为你的领导失职
because of your poor leadership.
我们都知道你唯一在意的恶意收购
We both know the only hostile takeover you care about
就是对这里的
is the one in here.
合个影吧
Take a picture,
因为明天这些名字就要撤下来了
because tomorrow morning, those letters are coming down.
他去哪儿了
Where the hell is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
格蕾琴  我发誓  如果你还想明天有工作
Gretchen, I swear, if you want to have a job tomorrow,
就最好告诉我哈维去哪了
you better tell me where Harvey is.
皮尔逊女士  我每周日都会为下周
Ms. Pearson, every Sunday I lay out all my outfits
准备好工作装  我也不想
for the coming week, and I have no intention
到了明天就没机会再穿了
of not wearing one of those babies tomorrow.
恕我直言
So with all due respect,
我真的不知道
I don't know.
好吧  如果你还想为下周准备衣服
Well, if you want to pick out your clothes for next week,
你最好把他找出来
you better find the hell out.
翻译： 王大可 潇湘月影 木浅薰  小酸奶
翻译：某羽 鱼小姐 香茗小焙 菲力
时间轴：风吹来的那片云     校对：油炸电风扇   潇湘月影
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第十集
哈维  哈维  等等
Harvey. Harvey, wait.
等等  我犯了个错误
Wait. I-I made a mistake.
你别碰我
Don't you touch me.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我知道这是你最后一次骗爸爸了
I understand you made a fool out of dad for the last time.
莉莉  让我试试  哈维
Lily, let me try. Harvey--
你滚出我父亲的房子
You get the hell out of my father's house.
鲍比  出去
Bobby, get--get out.
出去
Get out!
哈维  听我说
Harvey, listen to me.
你不清楚你在做什么
No, you don't know what you're doing.
我非常清楚我在做什么
I know exactly what I'm doing.
哈维  想想这对你父亲会造成什么影响
Harvey, think about what it would do to your father.
还有马库斯  他们受不了的
To Marcus. It'll kill them.
你以前就说过  说以后再也不会这么做了
You said that once before and you'd never do this again.
我知道我说了什么
I know what I said.
我也说过如果你再犯  我就告诉他们一切
And I said if you did I'd tell him everything,
我要告诉他们
And I'm going to.
哈维  我求求你
Harvey, I am begging you.
不要拆毁我们
Don't tear us all to pieces.
不要摧毁你的家庭
Don't destroy your family.
你居然敢把罪名扣到我头上
Don't you dare put this shit on me.
哈维
Harvey?
你刚刚在想什么呢
Where did you just go?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我只是想起了当年我得决定
I was just thinking about the time I had to decide
要不要把我母亲出轨的事
whether or not I should tell my father
告诉我父亲
that my mother was cheating on him.
也许我们应该谈谈这件事
And maybe we should talk about that.
我不是来谈这件事的
I didn't come here to talk about that.
我来这是想弄清楚我到底该不该辞职
I came here to figure out whether or not I should resign.
然后你想起了你的母亲
And then you started thinking about your mother.
如果你的大脑想到了这件事
And if your brain went to the one,
那这两者之间必然有关联
then it's connecting it to the other,
我们现在最好还是
and the best thing we can do right now
努力弄清楚为什么
is to try and figure out why.
我没这个时间
I don't have time for that.
哈维  你要求我给你空出一天来
Harvey, you asked me to block out the day
做紧急咨询  我照做了
for an emergency session, and I did.
我们有的是时间
We have time.
白色的石头最好
The white ones are best.
你只是来劝我进去的
You're just here to make me go in.
没错
I am.
有时候虽然我们还不够成熟
Because sometimes we make choices
却会被迫作出一些决定
we're not old enough to make,
然后我们会后悔
and then we regret them.
我不希望这种事发生在你的身上
I don't want that to happen to you.
为什么我会因为没进那个地方而后悔
Why would I regret not going into that place?
因为你有机会向你父母告别
'cause it's a chance to say good-bye to your parents.
我已经错过了
I already missed that.
迈克
Mike.
有时候  人们失去自己的所爱时
Sometimes when people lose someone they love,
会生他们的气
they get mad at them.
我没有生他们的气
I'm not mad at them.
我生上帝的气
I'm mad at God.
我理解你为什么会生上帝的气
I understand you're mad at God.
你可能都会生我的气
Maybe you're even mad at me, too.
但我是来给你点东西的
But I came out here to give you something.
圣威廉
St. William,
孤儿的守护神
Patron saint of orphans.
你知道他是谁
You know who this is.
我知道所有的守护神
I know who all the saints are,
可我不想要
and I don't want it.
我不想做孤儿
I don't want to be an orphan.
那就不要吧
Then don't take it.
因为实际上  孤儿都是孤独的
Because the truth is, orphans are alone,
可你不孤独
and you're not.
但是你不进去
But not going in there
也改变不了事实
isn't gonna change what happened.
现在  你的奶奶需要你
And right now, your grandmother needs you.
但如果你留在这里
But if you stay out here,
她今天就只能独自面对一切
she's gonna have to face today alone.
事情定下来了  哈维
Well, it's official, Harvey.
我的手指太老了
My fingers are way too old.
才没有呢
Like hell.
你还是比其他人强
You can still outplay anyone.
你真是太不会撒谎了
You're a terrible liar.
但我不得不承认
But I got to admit,
我还是喜欢在人群中看到我的儿子
I do love seeing my boy in the crowd.
爸爸  其实我想
Actually, dad, there's something
告诉你一些事
I wanted to talk to you about.
我也想和你说点事  非常重要
I got something for you, too. It's important.
乐队要解散了
The band's splitting up.
什么
What?
莱尼说他想和玛姬共同享受退休生活
Lenny says he wants to spend his golden years with Marge,
戴夫的手腕也没有好转  所以...
and Dave's wrist isn't getting any better, so--
那哈利呢
Well, what about Harry?
已经有别的乐团邀请哈利了
Harry's already got an offer from another group.
如果他们要他  那肯定也会要你
Well, if they'll take him, they'll take you.
你没有仔细听  哈维
You're not listening, Harvey.
我不想让他们收我
I don't want them to take me.
我想回家
I want to come home.
爸爸  音乐是你的生命啊
Dad, music is your life.
哈维  你爷爷死的时候
Look, Harvey, I'm the same age your grandfather was
就是我这个年纪
when he died,
而我已经浪费了太多的时间
and I've already spent way too much of my life
疏远了我的家人
away from my family.
别这么说  你是个超级棒的父亲
Don't start that. You've been a great father.
也许只能算得上够酷  算不上棒
Maybe the cool father, but...not a great one.
我知道现在补偿你已经太晚了
And now, I know it's too late to make that up to you.
我只是希望对于马库斯来说不算太晚
I'm just hoping it's not too late to make it up to Marcus.
这就是我要跟你说的
Anyway, that's my news.
你...你想跟我说什么
What--what did you want to talk about?
没什么  我认识了一个女孩
Nothing. I met a girl.
不错  她叫什么名字
Great. What's her name?
斯科特
Scottie.
只不过是异地恋  我还得自己想想明白
I'm just trying to figure out the long distance thing.
我只能告诉你  如果她是命中注定的那个人
All I can tell you there is, if she's the one,
你会知道的  就像我和你妈妈一样
you'll know, just like with me and your mother.
所以你没有告诉他吗
So you didn't tell him?
没有
No, I didn't.
但是你说那晚你决定要告诉他
But you said that was the night you decided to tell him.
我的确是在那晚决定的
That was the night I decided.
不  你说得好像都是一晚上发生的事
No, you said it as though it was all one night.
我告诉你都是一晚上的事
I told you it was all one night
因为我还是会在说到这事时习惯性撒谎
because I'm so used to lying whenever I tell this story.
我的年龄...
My age--
你为什么要撒谎
Why do you lie?
因为当时我已经是个成年人了
Because I was a grown man when it happened,
而成年人说话
and grown men keep their words
就会算话  而不会
when they say they're gonna do something,
因软弱而屈服
not give in to weakness.
但是你食言并不是因为软弱
But it wasn't weakness that made you break your word.
而是因为对你父亲的爱
It was love for your father.
那我不就是一个混蛋吗
Then aren't I an asshole?
因为两个星期后我把所有事都搞砸了
Because I ended up ruining everything two weeks later.
路易  我要跟你谈谈
Louis, I need to talk to you for a minute.
谈什么
About what?
杰克·索罗夫今天要投票
Jack Soloff is calling for a vote
决定是否撤销我管理合伙人的职位
to remove me as managing partner today.
什么
What?
你给他提名冠名合伙人
Why the hell would he do that
他为什么还要这么做
after you offered to make him name partner?
因为我没有给他提名冠名合伙人
Because I didn't offer to make him name partner.
我让他辞职
I told him to resign.
我们不都计划好了吗
What happened to our plan?
那不是我们的计划  路易
It wasn't our plan, Louis.
那只是你的荒唐想法
It was your insane idea,
我绝不可能照做
and I was never going to do it.
杰西卡
Jessica--
不  你听我说
No, you listen to me.
眼下的重点是
The matter at hand is
确保站在我们这边的人
making sure that we have more people on our side
比他和丹尼尔那边的人多
than he and Daniel have on theirs.
那我该做什么
What am I supposed to do now?
首先  你要严格完成
You are going to do exactly what I told you to do
我当初叫你做的事
in the first place.
你要找出丹尼尔的手上
You're gonna find out what Daniel has
究竟有那个狡猾混蛋的什么把柄
on that weaselly son of a bitch,
而且要在今晚七点前找到
and do it before 7:00 tonight.
因为我要是在那之前拉不到足够多的票
Because if I can't get enough votes before then,
唯一的解决方法就是除掉那个把柄
the only way we win is to make this whole thing go away.
取消我今天的安排
Cancel my day.
我们得谈谈
We have to talk.
我在学习呢  奶奶
I'm studying, grammy.
我才不在乎你说你在干什么
I don't care what you say you're doing.
什么叫我说我在干什么
What I say I'm doing?
沃克神父打来电话
Father Walker called me.
他说你最近很不老实
He said you've been acting out.
沃克神父是个神父
Father Walker's a priest.
嚼个口香糖他都觉得不老实
He thinks you're acting out if you're chewing gum.
我和他想的一样
Well, I agree with him.
可你不在学校  而我一直都考A
Yeah, and you're not at school and all I do is get As.
我不在乎你的成绩
I don't care what you're getting.
我在垃圾桶里找到了这些
I found these in the trash.
那又怎样
So what.
怎样
So what?
《小王子》《詹姆斯与大仙桃》
"The Little Prince," "James and the Giant Peach,"
迈克尔  你不是最喜欢看这些书吗
Michael, you love these books.
那是我小时候爱看的
Yeah, when I was a kid.
这些书
Those books were your connection
是你与父母的联系
to your mother and father.
我现在不想要了
Yeah, well, I don't want them anymore.
这本你也不要了吗
You don't want this one either?
我和你妈妈关系不是很好
Your mother and I didn't always get along,
但我知道你小时候她每晚
but I know that she read this to you every night
都读这本书给你听  她告诉我了
when you were little because she told me.
我也知道你一直不让我读给你听
And I also know that you'd never let me read it to you
因为你说过它是特别的
because you said it was so special.
我说了  我不是小孩子了
Like I said, I'm not a kid anymore.
迈克尔  我很担心你
Michael, I'm worried about you.
沃克神父也很担心
Father Walker is worried.
我不管沃克神父怎么想
I don't care what Father Walker thinks,
我也不在乎这些破书
and I don't care about these stupid books.
我在乎
Well, I do care,
你明天最好去找沃克神父谈谈
And I think you'd better go talk to Father Walker tomorrow
因为你没有全考A
because you're not getting all As.
历史考试他给了你F
He's giving you an F on your history paper.
路易  你怎么来了
Louis, what are you doing here?
史黛西怎么让你进来了
How did you get past Stacy?
她没敢拦
I walked right by her.
那么  有何贵干
Well, in that case, what can I do for you?
我想知道你手上有杰克·索罗夫什么把柄
I want to know what the hell you have on Jack Soloff.
除了他信任我  以及他相信
I have nothing on Jack other than his trust
我是比杰西卡更优秀的律师  别无他物
and confidence that I'm a better attorney than Jessica.
你闭嘴吧
Shut your mouth.
你都不配给她舔鞋
You're not fit to lick her boots.
随便  因为那是你的活  路易
Good, because that's your job, Louis,
不是我的
not mine.
听我说
Listen to me.
还记得我说过如果你不说
Remember when I told you I'd kill you
我就杀了你吗
if you so much as tell me the incorrect time?
赶紧告诉我杰克的把柄
Tell me what you have on Jack right now
否则十五秒内我就让你死在这儿
or you're dead in 15 seconds.
我记得你说过什么  路易
I remember when you did that, Louis.
而在那之后  我直接去找了我的律师
And right after that, I went straight to my attorneys
告诉他们你威胁要害我性命
and told them you had threatened my life.
如今你闯到我的办公室又干了一遍
And now, you've come into my office and done it again
还当着证人的面
in front of a witness.
什么证人
What witness?
史黛西  录下来了吗
Stacy, did you get that?
录下了
I got it.
在我看来
So as I see it,
一分钟内保安就会上来
security will be here in about 60 seconds.
所以你要是想杀我
So if you want to kill me,
只有趁现在了
now is your chance.
我发誓  我会找出
I swear to god, I will find out
杰克在你手上的把柄
what you're holding over Jack's head.
深表怀疑
I doubt that,
我非常怀疑你能不能在七点前找到
and I certainly doubt that you'll find it by 7:00.
所以与其告诉你杰克在我手上的把柄
So instead of me telling you what I have on Jack,
不如说说你在我手上的把柄
let me tell you what I have on you.
今天你投票支持我
You vote with me today
你妹妹的公司就安然无恙
and your sister's company lives.
-什么  -其实
- What? - Oh, it turns out
我客户想要进军蛋糕领域
my client is looking to get into the muffin business.
别把我妹妹扯进来
You leave my sister out of this.
没问题
Sure thing.
只要你投票撤杰西卡职
As long as you vote to remove Jessica.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
那我不仅会收购
Then I'm not only gonna buy it,
还会把她的公司大卸八块
I'm gonna rip that company of hers apart.
你个混蛋  她跟你毫无瓜葛
You son of a bitch! She never did anything to you.
是没有
No.
但你有
But you did.
杰西卡有
And Jessica did.
哈维有
And Harvey did.
所以选择权在你
So you have a choice,
律所  还是家人
Your firm or your family.
迈克尔
Michael?
好久不见
It's been a long time.
最近总有人喊我的全名
People have been calling me that a lot lately.
或许是个预兆
Maybe it's a sign.
有事吗
How can I help you?
我得找人谈谈
I need to talk to someone.
我希望在告解室里谈
I was hoping to do it under the confessional.
离你上次告解有多久了
How long has it been since your last confession?
这话不是应该在开始告解之后再问吗
Aren't you supposed to ask me that after we started?
我们已经开始了
We have started.
坐吧
Have a seat.
就在这里
Here?
不行吗
Why not?
告解是为了净化灵魂
Confession's meant to be good for the soul
没人规定一定要在小黑屋里
and no one's ever said anything about it having to be done
才能完成
in a little dark box.
请坐
Please.
你给我F
You gave that paper an F?
明明可以得A的
It deserves an A.
你上周二翘了一整个下午的课
What about the fact that you cut the entire afternoon
-又怎么解释  -我约了医生
- Last tuesday? - I had a doctor's appointment.
你还有你祖母写的假条
You even had a note from your grandmother.
没错
That's right, I did.
问题是  迈克尔
The problem is, Michael,
你祖母昨天给我写了一张便条
your grandmother wrote me a note yesterday
感谢我让她的读书俱乐部使用图书馆
thanking me for letting her book club use the library.
这两个签名
And those two signatures,
完全不一样
they don't look the same at all.
好吧  既然你这么确定我是翘课
Okay, well, if you're so sure I did this,
那为什么只给我一个F
then why are you only giving me an F
没勒令我停学呢
and not suspending me?
因为我觉得你选择在家长会这天翘课
Because I don't think it's a coincidence that
并不是一个巧合
you chose to cut class on parent-teacher conference day.
跟那个没关系
That had nothing to do with it.
迈克  你祖母跟我说了
Mike, your grandmother told me about
你扔掉的那些书
the books you threw out.
全世界的父母都希望自己的孩子
Every parent in the world is obsessed
清理自己的房间
with their kid cleaning their room.
我只是在清理房间
I actually do it,
你们两个太大惊小怪了
and the two of you make a federal case out of it.
你扔书不是为了清理房间
You didn't throw out those books to clean.
而是因为你看见别的孩子
You did it because you saw those kids out there
都有父母
with their parents,
而你承受不了那种痛苦
and you just couldn't deal with that pain.
所以你翘了课  回到家
So you cut class, you went home,
把那些书都扔了
and you threw away the books.
你又不知道我做了什么
You don't know what I did.
我知道的是  你父母从前每周日都会过来
What I do know is that your parents came here every Sunday
捐钱来换得那身制服
and donated money to pay for that uniform
因为他们想让你在这里接受教育
because they wanted you to be here getting an education
不是让你翘课
and not cutting class.
我每门课的成绩
I've gotten a perfect grade on every assignment
都非常好
I've ever gotten, all right?
我用不着去上你的破课
And I don't need to go to your stupid class to do it.
我可以让你停学
I could have suspended you,
这比打F的惩罚要重多了
and that would have been much worse than an F.
你要么得F  要么就停学
But you're getting one or you're getting the other.
不如你省下一晚上责怪我的时间
So why don't you take one night off from blaming me,
好好想想你要怎么做
and you decided what it is that you're gonna do?
哈维
Harvey,
你在这里做什么
what are you doing here?
我想求你件事
I wanted to ask you something.
我想知道我可不可以在实习期间
I was wondering if I could stay with you
跟你一起住
while I do my clerkship.
你想暑期跟我一起住
You want to stay with me for the summer?
我保证低调到你都察觉不出我的存在
I promise you won't even know I'm there.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你知不知道
Do you have any idea
如果被这里的人发现了
what the people around here would think
会怎么想吗
if they found out?
谁说他们会知道了
Who says they're gonna find out?
反正也没人
I mean, no one knows anything
了解你的私生活
about your personal life anyway.
哈维  到底怎么了
Harvey, what's going on?
家里不太顺
Things aren't good at home.
你弟弟的事吗
Your brother?
是我父母
It's my parents.
哈维  我知道
Listen, Harvey, I know what it's like
生活在不和谐的家庭是什么感受
to be living in a home that's not right,
我也知道你可能想要居中调解
and I also know that you might be tempted to fix things.
但这不是孩子应该做的事
But it's not up to the children to fix things.
如果是呢
What if it was?
那么那两个人有问题
Then there's something wrong with those two people.
不  不是这样的
No, there isn't.
是其中一个有问题
There's something wrong with one of them,
我不知道该不该告诉另一个
and I don't know whether to tell the other one or not.
哈维  我无法告诉你该做什么
Look, Harvey, I can't tell you what you should do.
但我可以告诉你  如果你来为我工作
But I can tell you if you come work for me,
你将不得不面对一些困难的谈话
You're gonna have to have some difficult conversations.
工作是工作  家庭是家庭
That's work, this is family.
没有比对家人开诚布公更困难的谈话了
There are no more difficult conversations than that.
但我想让你知道
But for the record,
如果你来这里工作
if you do come work here,
我们也会成为家人
we're gonna be family, too.
你爸爸和马库斯随时都会回来
Your father and Marcus will be here any minute,
我还做了你最爱吃的奶酪鸡
and, oh, I made your favorite, chicken parm.
我很高兴他们不在这里
I'm glad they're not here.
让我有机会告诉你
It'll give me a chance to tell you that
他们在场时我可以装
I'll pretend when they're here,
咱俩独处时我可不想再装下去
but I am not gonna pretend when we're alone.
哈维  拜托  我毕竟是你妈妈
Harvey, please, I'm still your mother.
不  你不是
No, you're not.
看谁来了
Hey, hey, hey, look who's here.
我以为你今晚要工作到很晚
I thought you were working late tonight.
你好啊  傻逼
What's up, douche nozzle?
哈维  你还记得
You remember Bobby from down at the shop,
楼下汽修厂的鲍比吧
don't you, Harvey?
他来帮我们修野马老爷车
He's helping us get the old Mustang up and running.
没错  哈维  野马是我的了
That's right, harvey, I'm getting the Mustang.
你要是以为自己能有机会
And if you think you're ever getting behind the wheel
开着过过瘾...
of that car--
我这辈子都不会去开那辆车
I'm never gonna get behind the wheel of that car.
因为你嫉妒
Because you're jealous.
因为那辆车就是坨屎
Because that car's a piece of shit.
哈维  怎么说话呢
Harvey, watch your mouth.
莉儿  多了一个人盘子够用吗
Lil, do we have enough for an extra plate?
当然  你好吗  鲍比
Sure. How you doing, Bobby?
等我把手上的油洗干净就好了
I'll be good as soon as I get this grease off my hands.
洗手间在哪来着
Where's the bathroom again?
过道尽头  鲍比
It's down the hall, Bobby.
知道吗
You know what?
不需要多加盘子了  我不吃
We don't need an extra plate 'cause I'm not eating.
你说什么呢  你回来这么早
What are you talking about? You're home early.
你妈妈还做了奶酪鸡
Your mother made chicken parm.
那你吃呗
Well, why don't you eat it?
因为我再也受不了奶酪鸡了
Because I can't stand chicken parm anymore.
你要去哪  哈维
Where you going? Harvey!
这里可还是我的家
This is still my house, you know.
是吗
Is it?
所以别人知道你的事
So other people know about you?
不是所有人都清楚我的一切  不过...
Not everyone knows everything, but...
有人知道我没有法学文凭
People know that I don't have a law degree.
你说得这么轻描淡写的
You say that as though it were just a technicality.
你说的像是在批评我
And you say that as if you're judging me.
你来这里不就是为了这个吗
Isn't that what you came here for?
我是来寻求建议
I came here for advice.
你说你是来告解的
You said you came here to confess.
不过没关系  因为如果...
But it doesn't matter, because if--
如果你想赦免你的罪
Well, if you're looking for absolution,
我做不到
I can't give it to you.
为什么
Why not?
因为只有悔悟的人才能接受赦免
Because absolution requires contrition,
但我没听出你觉得自己
and I'm not hearing that you even think
做过什么错事
you've done anything wrong.
因为用我的才智帮助别人
Because using my brain to help people
并不是做错事
isn't doing anything wrong.
你不是在用你的才智帮助别人
You're not using your brain to help people.
你是在愚弄别人
You're using it to fool people,
然后你还想让我因此而说你是个好人
and you want me to tell you that you're a good person for it.
我就是个好人
I am a good person.
你是那种什么好事都想占尽的人
You're a person that wants to have their cake and eat it, too.
但恐怕我这里没好处给你
And I'm afraid that I'm all out of cake with you.
这话什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是说我时常在想
It means that I've often wondered
那天没有报警让你被抓走
whether or not I did the right thing
我到底做的对不对
by not having you arrested that day.
那会彻底毁了我的人生的
That would have completely screwed up my life.
你现在的人生就不叫毁了吗
Oh, and look at how not screwed up it is right now.
你想知道我是什么样的人吗
You want to know what kind of man I am?
你想见我吗  神父
You wanted to see me, Father?
是的
Yes, I did.
我希望请你解释一下
I was hoping you could explain why
为什么我们的募捐箱里少了936美元
we're missing $936 from the collection box.
我没法解释
I can't.
那就奇了  因为这箱子就在我桌子里
Well, that's odd, because this box was in my desk,
而我在我桌子上
and I also found this
找到了这个
on my desk.
迈克尔  下一次你想表达什么信息
Michael, the next time you want to send a message,
在我桌上留张条就好了
just leave me a note.
制服并不是信息  我只是归还给你
The uniform's not a message. I'm just returning it.
你说我有两条路可选
You said I had two options,
要么得F  要么就停学
get an F or get suspended.
但我想到了第三条路
But I thought of a third.
你要退学吗
So you're dropping out?
不  我要转去公立学校
No, I'm going to public school.
而且我并不是说我拿了那笔钱
And I'm not saying that I took that cash,
但就算我拿了  那我也是足够聪明会算数
but if I did, I'd be smart enough to do the math.
我父母每周往募捐盘里放三美元
My parents put $3 in the collection plate every week.
每周三美元  一年52周  一共六年
$3 a week for 52 weeks for six years--
一共936美元
$936.
那我会想这些钱属于我父母
And I would have thought that belonged to my parents
我只是把这些钱拿回来
and I would have just been taking it back.
要知道我完全可以报警让你抓
You know, I could have you arrested.
那就尽管报警吧
Then do it.
迈克尔  你我都知道你有多聪明
Michael, we both know how smart you are,
但聪明和智慧是有区别的
but there's a difference between intelligence and wisdom.
而如果想不明白这一点
And if you don't figure that out eventually,
你将来遇到的问题可要比不及格大得多
you're gonna have a lot bigger problems than an f,
因为你没法聪明过...
because you can't outsmart--
上帝吗
God?
我知道
I know.
我知道你不相信上帝
I know you don't believe in God,
所以我们就称其为...
So let's just call them...
因果
Consequences.
再见  神父
Good-bye, Father.
你什么时候想报警  知道去哪里找我
You want to call the police, you know where to find me.
反正他们也不是
Wouldn't be the first time
第一次给奶奶带去坏消息了
they came to give grammy some bad news.
你一直没有花吗
You never spent it.
一分都没花
Not a penny.
下去
Get out.
下去  哈维  你来跟我打
Hey, get out! Harvey, you and me are going.
现在
Right now.
不  我们不打
No, we're not.
要打
Yes, we are.
不管你想不想
And it's happening whether you like it or not.
想告诉我你在家里发脾气
Now, you wanna tell me what was going on
是怎么回事吗
with that bullshit back at the house?
什么怎么回事
What bullshit?
我只是不饿  所以就走了
I wasn't hungry so I just left.
我才不信呢
I'm not buying it.
我知道你肯定有事
I know something's up with you.
没事
Nothing's up.
没事吗
Nothing?
你弟弟那么高兴见到你
Your little brother was excited to see you
你却连那么点时间也不给他
and you didn't give him the time of day.
马库斯高兴是因为他可以开鲍比的车
Marcus was excited to get Bobby's car.
你从什么时候开始对鲍比有意见了
Since when you got something against Bobby?
他又没对你做什么
He never did anything to you.
别管了  爸爸
Just let it go, dad.
我什么时候开始不能管了
Since when do I do that?
你又什么时候有时间在家管什么了
Since when were you around not to?
你说什么
Excuse me?
我说别管了
I said let it go.
我不会就这么不管了
I'm not letting it go!
你对我无礼
You disrespected me,
对你弟弟和你妈妈无礼
and you disrespected your brother and your mother
还对我们的客人无礼
and our guest.
我知道你肯定有什么事
Now, I know something's up with you.
我想知道是什么
I want to know what it is.
没什么事
It's nothing.
肯定不是没事
It's not nothing!
你为什么非要这样做
Why are you doing this?
因为我儿子有问题
'Cause there's something wrong with my boy.
我有问题
Something's wrong with me?
那你呢
What about you?
你怎么会连自己家里  眼皮底下的事情
How can you not see what is going on under your nose
都视而不见呢
in your own goddamn house?
好了  儿子  停下
All right. Son, stop!
我让她停  而这话本不该我去说
I told her to stop, but I shouldn't have had to.
本不该我去说的
It's shouldn't have been me!
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很对不起
I'm so sorry.
你让她停下什么
You told her to stop what?
你妈妈干了什么
What was your mother doing?
鲍比
Bobby.
然后你父母的婚姻就结束了吗
So your parents' marriage ended?
早就该结束了
It should have ended sooner.
哈维  我不是要为你妈妈辩护
Harvey, I'm not defending your mother,
但如果你信守诺言没有说出来
but what if you'd kept that promise
而且她和鲍比分手了呢
and then she broke it off with Bobby?
那又有什么区别
What difference does it make?
区别就是
Well, the difference is
你不用那样告诉你父亲
you didn't have to tell your father like that.
我那样告诉他是因为我别无选择
Yeah, I told him like that because I had no choice.
不不不  那样告诉他是你自己的选择
No, no, no, no, telling him like that was your choice.
他在攻击我
He was attacking me.
那你可以放弃反抗
Well, you could have dropped your guard.
我才不会那样做呢
I wasn't gonna do that.
-他是你父亲  -我不在乎
- He was your father. - I don't care!
-为什么  -因为我永远不会拱手认输
- Why? - Because I don't lay down!
所以你没有用更缓和的方式告诉他
And instead of telling him gently
没有冷静地作出决定
and making a decision calmly,
而是更深地伤害了你父亲
you hurt your father even more.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我是说或许你想起这个故事
I'm saying that maybe you're remembering this story
是想告诉自己
to tell yourself that your decision with Forstman
你跟傅滋曼的协议不是认输
isn't about laying down.
你会跟他对抗到底
It's about something more.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
你永远不会相信这件事
You're never going to believe this.
哈维今天问我能不能和我一起住
Harvey asked if he could live with me today.
令我意外的是你竟然没答应
I'm surprised you didn't say yes.
什么
What?
既然你已经驻扎在办公室了
You already live at the office.
为何不把办公室带回家
Why not just bring it home with you?
奎汀  我告诉过你
Quentin, I told you,
你比我的工作更重要
you mean more to me than work.
但事实胜于雄辩
Well, actions speak louder than words.
我嫁给你了
I married you.
没错
You did.
但哈维还有律所里其他人知道吗
But does Harvey or anyone else at the office know that?
或者有任何人知道我的存在吗
Or even know that I exist?
你知道我很注重个人隐私
You know I'm a private person.
我想分隔这两部分的生活
I like to keep those parts of my life separate.
但就我所知隔离但平等在外头行不通
What I know is, separate but equal didn't work out there,
在这里也一样不行
and it's not working in here.
你这话是什么意思
Where are you going with this?
别明知故问  杰西卡
You know where this is going, Jessica,
这么长时间了你明白的
where it's been going for a long time.
我想离婚
I want a divorce.
什么
What?
我们的婚姻持续不下去了
This isn't working anymore.
这和丽莎有关吗
Does this have anything to do with Lisa?
没有  这与我们俩有关
No. This has to do with us.
你是指我吧
Oh, you mean me.
没错
I do.
你就能一心扑在你最看重的事情上了
Now you can focus on what really matters to you...
你的事业
Your career.
杰西卡  能和你聊几句吗
Jessica, can I talk to you?
我猜你还没有找到
I take it you haven't found out
哈德曼掌握的杰克的把柄
what Hardman has on Jack.
确实还没  但有其他事情
I haven't, but there's something else.
没关系了
Doesn't matter.
我争取到了票数
I got us the votes.
真的吗
You did?
我去找了保罗·波特劝他
I went to Paul Porter and I turned him
还有跟随他的另外三票支持我们
and the three votes that he comes with.
那我们三票领先了吗
So we're up by three?
没有  加上哈维才领先一票
No, including Harvey, we're up by one.
不是这样
No, we're not.
哈德曼要对付埃斯特的公司
Hardman's going after Esther's company.
除非你投票反对我  否则他不会罢手
And he's not going to back off unless you vote against me.
-路易  -我知道你要说什么
- Louis-- - I know what you're gonna say.
我们能阻止他
We can stop it.
但我找了杰夫瑞让他别卖股份
But I went to Jeffrey to get him to not sell his shares,
他说哈德曼愿意多给40%的价钱收购
and he told me that Hardman's offering 40% over asking.
即使杰夫瑞答应不卖  还有其他人卖
Jeffrey agreed not to sell, but everyone else will.
假如哈德曼买不到股份
If Hardman can't get the stocks,
他就会去收购经销商
he's gonna buy the distributor,
如果他收购不了经销商
and if he can't buy the distributor,
他会针对公司的合同
he's gonna go after the contracts.
-路易  -傅滋曼是他的靠山
- Louis-- - Forstman is his backer!
我知道
I know.
既然你知道他有无限的资源
Well then, you know that he has unlimited resources,
我不能加入这场四面是敌的战斗
and I can't fight a war on multiple fronts.
我本可以告诉你的是如果你站我这边
And I could tell you that if you side with me,
我们能想出法子救埃斯特的公司
we'll figure out a way to save Esther's company.
但我也有妹妹
But I have a sister, too.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
路易
Louis...
不管发生什么
Whatever happens,
我希望你知道...
I want you to know...
皮尔逊总是会把利特当作
Pearson will always consider Litt
她的好伙伴的
her partner.
杰西卡
Jessica.
如果这次不是他妹妹
If it had been anybody other than his sister,
他肯定不会考虑...
he would never even consider--
我知道  唐娜
I know, Donna.
你不用替他道歉
And you don't have to apologize for him
因为我明白丹尼尔·哈德曼有多混蛋
because I know what a bastard Daniel Hardman is.
有什么能帮你的吗
Is there anything I can do?
有一件事
Yes.
在投票前我们还有时间
We still have some time before the vote.
我上午让格蕾琴去找哈维
I asked Gretchen to find Harvey this morning.
但我拜托错了人
I asked the wrong person.
我会找到他的
I'll find him.
我就知道这是个错误
I knew this was a mistake.
我不该来这里
I never should have come here.
迈克尔  你其实不必来这里
Michael, you didn't actually have to come here.
我已经清楚你的故事了
I already knew your story.
特雷弗半年前来见过我
Trevor came to see me six months ago.
我知道
Yeah, I know that.
但你不知道他讲得最多的是
Yeah, but you didn't know he spent most of that time
他为发生在你身上的事情
talking about you or the fact that he blames himself
感到深深的自责
for everything that happened to you.
或许他应该自责
Well, maybe he should.
或许你该责怪自己
Maybe you should blame yourself.
没错  或许每次地震每场战争
Right, and maybe I should blame myself
我都该责怪自己
for every earthquake or every war.
你的虚荣也够了  迈克尔
That's enough of the vanity, okay, Michael.
-虚荣  -对  虚荣  自我放纵
- Vanity? - Yeah, vanity, self-indulgence,
随便叫什么吧  反正从那晚之后
whatever you want to call feeling sorry for yourself
-你就自怨自艾  -你竟敢这么说
- ever since that night... - How dare you.
-就是这样你才会让身陷这境地  -不
- Because that's exactly why you're in this position right now. - No!
我身处这种境地是特雷弗害我的
I'm in this position because Trevor put me in this position.
不  迈克尔  不是这样的
No, Michael, no.
这就是你和特雷弗的差别所在
That's the difference between you and Trevor.
他其实接受这一切都是自己的选择
He's actually accepted that his choices were his own,
也就是说他真想去改变自己的生活
which means he actually wants to change his life.
你觉得我不想改变吗
You think I don't want to change?
那你说我现在在这里做什么
Why the hell do you think I'm here?
我不知道  你为什么来这儿
I don't know. Why are you here?
我说了  我需要建议
I told you, I want advice.
不不  人们不需要通过告解的保护
No, no, people do not need the protection of the confessional
来获得建议
to get advice.
我那么做是为了保护你
I did that to protect you.
你那么做是为了保护你自己
No, you did that to protect you.
所以你现在告诉我  你为什么来这里
So you tell me right now, why are you here?
-一言难尽  -一言可尽
- It's not that simple. - It is that simple.
-我说不清  -你为什么来这里
- I can't. - Why are you here?
因为我害怕
Because I'm afraid!
你在怕什么  迈克尔
What are you afraid of, Michael?
他们都弃我而去
They left me all alone.
现在你找到了爱你的人
And now you've found someone who loves you...
如果你不再是这样的自己
and if you stop being who you are,
你害怕她也会抛下你
you're afraid she'll abandon you, too.
我该怎么做  神父
What am I gonna do, Father?
跟我来  迈克尔
Come with me, Michael.
我给你看个东西
I want to show you something.
你为什么告诉他
Why'd you tell him?
他有权知道
He needed to know.
他需要的是我们这个家
What he needed was for us to be a family.
家不是建立在谎言上的
Families aren't built on lies.
现在地基连谎言都不是  而是一摊烂泥了
Well, now all we are is built on shit
因为你这么做  除了你之外谁都不开心
Because nobody's happy about what you did except for you.
我这么做不是为了我自己
I didn't do this for me.
你就是无法忍受
You couldn't stand that
这一切都将是我的了的事实
I was about to have them all to myself.
你觉得我这么做是为了和你抢什么吗
You think I did this to take something away from you?
你就是抢走了我的东西
You did take something away from me.
你还不明白
You don't get it.
你可以回你的法律学校
You get to go back to law school,
通过律师资格考试
and you're gonna pass the bar,
过你前途光明的美好生活
and you're gonna go live your big hotshot life,
只剩我一个人孤零零留在这里
and I'm gonna be stuck here on my own.
-你不是孤身一人  -是吗
- You're not on your own. - Really?
不知道你注意到没有  但妈妈刚走了
I don't know if you noticed, but mom just left
爸爸也不愿意出屋子  我还有谁
and dad's not coming out of his room, so who's here for me?
所以两周后我在市里租了间房子
So two weeks later I got a place in the city,
搬了出来  再也没回去过
I moved out, and I never went back.
这一切之后  你却丢下了你父亲和你弟弟
You left your brother and your father alone after all that?
我也不想这么做的
I didn't want to.
那你为什么还这么做
Then why did you?
因为我无法接受
Because I couldn't take knowing that
是我把一切搞得支离破碎这个事实
I was the one that tore everything to pieces.
现在你觉得如果你辞职  一切又会重演
And you think you'll be doing that again if you resign?
如果我辞职就是会重演
I will be doing that again if I resign.
我认为后退一步
Well, I think stepping down
并不会破坏一切
isn't tearing everything to pieces.
我认为这是个拯救一切的机会
I think it's a chance to keep everything together.
是她给了我重新开始的机会
She gave me my start.
哈维  有次我说杰西卡听起来
Harvey, I once commented that Jessica sounds like
真是个女强人
a hell of a woman,
然后你说  那又怎样
and you said, "What does it matter?"
是你给我留下了她是个
Well, you're the one who led me to believe
女强人的印象
she's a hell of a woman.
也许是有理由的
Maybe you did it for a reason.
什么理由
What reason?
为了让我说她应该会理解
For me to suggest that maybe she'll understand
你离开并不代表你不在乎她了
that you leaving doesn't mean that you don't care about her.
恰恰代表你在乎
It means that you do.
那如果我告诉你不是为了这个呢
And what if that's not why I told you all this?
如果是你错了呢
What if you're wrong?
那我就承认错误
Then I'll be wrong.
那你也一定能解决此事
And you'll be able to handle that.
我以前经常就待在这个屋呢
I spent a lot of time here.
你还记得这里
You remember this place?
我过目不忘
I remember everything.
我知道  迈克尔
I know you do, Michael.
我一直都知道你与众不同
I was always aware of what a special child you were.
这里一点都没变啊
Hasn't changed a bit.
一点都没吗
Hasn't it?
什么意思
What are you talking about?
迈克尔  我觉得你来见我
Michael, I think you came to see me
是因为当人们遇到困难的时候
because when people are in crisis
总会怀念曾经的拥有
they're searching for something more,
拥有但失去的那些
usually something they've lost.
我失去了父母  再也找不回来了
I lost my parents, and I'm not getting them back.
不  迈克尔  你失去的是信念
No, Michael, you lost your faith.
奶奶
Grammy.
深情怀念
伊迪丝·罗斯
你离开学校的第二天
The day after you left school
她就把钱还回来了
she gave me the money back.
她唯一的要求是让我们用其中部分
Her only request was that we use some of it
买下这个书架
to buy this bookcase
来保留这些书
to keep these books together.
这些是我父亲的书
They're my father's books.
还有你母亲的
And your mother's.
我一直不明白她为什么这么做
I never knew why she did it.
现在我明白了
And now I do.
迈克  如果你在担心自己一旦改变
Michael, if you're worried about Rachel leaving you,
瑞秋就会离开你
if you stop doing what you're doing,
我想她不会的
I don't think she will.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我有信念
'Cause I have faith.
有事吗
Can I help you?
我只是
I was just--
他人呢
Where is he?
你问谁
Where is who?
哈维
Harvey.
拜托  我找他有急事
Please, it's an emergency.
抱歉  他不在这里
Well, I'm sorry, he's not here,
而且恐怕我并不知道他去了哪里
and I'm afraid I don't know where he went.
抱歉  我只是
I'm sorry, I just--
你介意我在这里坐一会儿吗
Do you mind if I just sit here for a minute?
请便
Of course.
也许你比我更了解现在的状况吧
You probably know more about what's going on that I do, don't you?
抱歉  这个问题我不能回答
I'm sorry, I can't respond to that.
既然我也来了
As long as I'm here...
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢我什么
For what?
几周前哈维终于原谅了我
A few weeks ago Harvey finally forgave me
去为路易工作的事
for going to Louis.
我知道如果不是他来找了你
And I know he never would have done that
肯定不会的
if he hadn't come to see you.
抱歉  这个问题我也不能回答
I'm sorry, I can't respond to that either.
其实你已经回答了
You just did.
再次谢谢你  为你此刻的想法
And thank you again for what you're thinking.
我在想什么
And what is that?
你在想如果不是我
That he never would have come to see you
他也不会来找你
if it hadn't been for me.
你真能读懂人心
You really can do that.
是的
Yeah, I can.
事实上  我还知道你现在在想什么
In fact, I can tell you what you're thinking right now.
什么
What is that?
你在想两件事  事实上
You're thinking two things, actually.
其一  这女人要当心理咨询师肯定很厉害
One, this woman would make an excellent therapist.
其二
And two...
哈维不知道他错过了多好的人
Harvey has no idea what he's missing.
看来哈维不会来了
Well, it seems Harvey won't be joining us,
所以不如现在开始吧
so we may as well get started.
我们今天聚集一堂是因为
We're here because there's a concern
大家担心我已不再将公司利益放在首位
that I no longer have the best interests of the firm at heart
而是只关心某些个人的
but am instead focused on the selfish interests
私人利益
of certain individuals.
对那些这么想的人
For those of you who feel that way,
此刻我也无法做什么
there's not much I could do
来改变你们的看法
at this point to change your minds.
所以我只能说
So...I'll say...
希望我还有幸能继续为律所服务
I hope it remains my pleasure to serve this firm.
我觉得我们该投票了
I think it's time we vote.
你要不说点什么来让他们改主意
Well, if you're not gonna say anything to change their mind,
那我来
Then I will.
你真的来了
You made it.
什么也阻止不了我
Wouldn't have missed it for the world.
好吧  你来了
Okay, fine, you're here,
但你也没法说什么来为她辩护
but there's nothing that says you can plead her case.
也没规定他不能说话
And there's nothing that says he can't,
所以你干嘛不坐下听听
so why don't you sit your ass down?
那就说吧  赶紧发表完你的演讲
Go ahead, then, get your speech over with
我们就可以投票了
so we can get to the vote.
我没什么演讲  只有这个
No speech, just this.
一封解约书
A termination letter.
此时此刻  狙击我们客户的公司
As of now, the company that's been targeting our clients
已经不由丹尼尔·哈德曼代理了
is no longer represented by Daniel Hardman.
-胡说  -那你打给他问问
- Bullshit. - Go ahead, call him.
当然  打电话可能得花点时间
Of course, it might take a while
因为你得经过监狱总机
since you've got to go through the prison switchboard
才能联系到他
to get ahold of him.
是的  没错
Yep, that's right.
那就是杰克·索罗夫和丹尼尔·哈德曼合作的人
That's the kind of man Jack Soloff and Daniel Hardman
已经进了监狱的家伙
do business with, one who's already behind bars.
我说清楚吧
Look, let me be clear.
此次对律所的攻击  其实是冲我个人来的
The attack on this firm was an attack on me.
《好奇的乔治》  作者H·A·雷
丹尼尔为他离所的事责怪我
Daniel blamed me for having to leave this firm,
所以想在伤我最痛的地方下手
so he was trying to hit me where it hurt the most,
迈克尔  要记得  关心你的人
永远会在你身边帮助你走出困境  爱你的爸爸妈妈
也就是这间律所
namely this firm
跟我的合伙人及朋友
and my partners and my friends.
但这一切都结束了
But that's over.
他已经没有钱
He has no more money,
没有力量  没有朋友了
no more power, no more friends.
你们每个人  将要投票决定
All of you, you're about to vote on whether
杰西卡是否应该继续管理这间律所
Jessica should continue running this firm.
我知道你们中有些人认为  她对我的行为
Now, I know some of you think that she's turned a blind eye
以及我冒的风险睁一只眼闭一只眼
to my behavior and--and the risks I've taken,
可你们试图替换她才是最大的冒险
but for you to remove her would be the greatest risk of all.
因为我知道
Because if there's one thing I know,
杰西卡·皮尔逊在乎这间律所
it's that Jessica Pearson cares about this firm
和律所中的每个人
and everyone in it.
因为对她而言  我们不仅是同事
Because to her, we're not just colleagues
甚或朋友
or even friends,
而是家人
we're family.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
我们来投票吧
Let's vote.
杰西卡  我觉得我们不需要不记名投票
Jessica, I don't think we're gonna be needing the ballots.
我们每个人都知道自己的立场
I think everybody knows where they stand.
所有支持杰西卡留下的人  举手
All in favor of Jessica staying.
那我想这里所有人都很乐意
Then I guess everyone here is happy
事情保持原状  除了一位
keeping things the way they are, except for one.
太好了你在这儿  我有话跟你说
I'm glad you're here. I need to tell you something.
无论要说什么  我给你这个之后
Whatever it is, it might not matter
就都不重要了
after I give you this.
那是什么
What is it?
哈维  你不光给了我梦想
Harvey, you didn't just give me my dream.
还给了我一个家
You gave me a family.
但我终有一天会有自己的家
But I'm gonna have a family of my own someday,
我不能让这些事悬在他们头上
and I can't have all of this hanging over their heads.
你要辞职
You're resigning.
是的
I am.
你记得有次你问我为什么雇你
You know, you once asked me why I hired you,
我跟你说  因为生活的高度在这里
and I told you it was because life is like this
而我在这里
and I like this.
哈维  拜托  你不可能劝我...
Harvey, please, you can't convince me--
让我说完
Let me finish.
能有这个高度
It was like this
原因不在于我们担的风险
not because of the risk we're taking.
而是因为你是你
it's because of who you are.
所以你不失望
So you're not disappointed?
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
说了那么多  你不这么做
After that speech, if you hadn't done this,
我也会踢你走
I'd be kicking you out.
而且再说一句
And for the record,
你不是这里唯一获得更多家人的人
You're not the only one who got more family out of this deal.
你真的好美
You really are so beautiful.
荧光灯底下没人美的
No one's beautiful in fluorescent light.
你就美
You are.
你的神秘冒险怎么样了
So how did your mysterious adventure go?
得到你想要的东西了吗
Did you get what you needed?
得到了
I did.
这是什么
What's this?
提前的结婚礼物
Early wedding present.
迈克  这是...
Mike, this is--
我辞职信的副本
A copy of my letter of resignation.
如果这跟克莱尔
If this is about the thing with Claire
或者我跟我妈妈的争吵有关...
or the fight that I got into with my mom--
没关系
It's not.
这只关于我们要好好开始我们的生活
This is about us starting our life right,
干干净净地开始
with a clean slate.
你不必为我这么做
You don't have to do this for me.
我不是为你
I'm not.
是为了我们
I'm doing it for us.
因为只要你支持我...
Because as long as you're with me--
我支持你
I'm with you.
那就让我跟我的办公室说再见吧
Well then, let me go say good-bye to my office,
然后我们回家
and let's go home.
奥登·斯佩克特
我们还没来得及庆祝你就走了
You walked out before we got a chance to celebrate.
抱歉  只是我那一天过得太艰难了
I'm sorry. It's just been a long day.
哈维  你到底是怎么从傅滋曼那儿
Harvey, how exactly did you get that termination letter
拿到解约书的
from Forstman?
我们明早再谈吧
Let's talk about it in the morning.
哈维
Harvey.
我同意辞职
I agreed to step down.
当然不行
Absolutely not.
你不能辞职
You are not going to step down.
这事定了
It's done.
没什么定了
Nothing's done.
杰西卡  你为这律所付出了一切
Jessica, please, you've given up everything for this firm.
该有人为你付出点东西了
It's time someone gave up something for you.
我不想让你做那个付出的人呢
What if I don't want you to be the one to do that?
那就原谅我  因为我要做
Then forgive me, because I am.
好消息是迈克·罗斯要离开
Good news is Mike Ross is leaving.
我从没想过我会这么说
I never thought I'd say this,
但现在
but this moment,
它看起来不是什么好消息
it doesn't feel like good news.
迈克尔·詹姆斯·罗斯
Micheal James Ross?
怎么
Yes?
你因共谋诈骗被捕了
You're under arrest for conspiracy of fraud.